Narrator: 2
Capital punishment
Speaker: About 75% of countries around the world have completely abolished capital punishment.
They have not executed anyone within the last ten years,
or use it only in exceptional circumstances, for example, for war crimes.
Places where the death penalty still exists include some states in the USA,
some Caribbean and African countries, and the majority of countries in Asia.
In the United States, the electric chair was introduced as a more humane alternative to hanging,
but has been almost entirely replaced by lethal injection.
In the USA, prisoners may wait for years on death row before execution is carried out,
due to the complex appeals system.
Nearly a quarter die of natural causes while awaiting execution.